<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on Hyper Potato&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://hyper-potato.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on Hyper Potato&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hyper-potato.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats vs Dogs Classification</title>
      <link>https://hyper-potato.github.io/2019-11-28-cat-or-dog-classification-dnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hyper-potato.github.io/2019-11-28-cat-or-dog-classification-dnn/</guid>
      <description>Image classification exercise I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna lie. I&amp;rsquo;m more of a dog person. Better know how to tell the difference. 😂 Here we go.
Introduction This is an Image classification exercise. I will play with an expired Kaggle competition. The code is available in a jupyter notebook here. You will need to download the data from the Kaggle competition. https://www.kaggle.com/c/dogs-vs-cats/. The dataset contains 25,000 images of dogs and cats (12,500 from each class).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Visitors for Restaurants</title>
      <link>https://hyper-potato.github.io/2019-12-30-restaurants-visitors-predictive-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hyper-potato.github.io/2019-12-30-restaurants-visitors-predictive-model/</guid>
      <description>#For Suckers for Sashimi Like Me!
1. Project Definition &amp;amp; Introduction When someone opens a restaurant, their focus is likely on making high-quality food that will make their customers happy. However, this does not cover all the problems they encounter. How do they effectively schedule the staff? How do they know the quantity of ingredients to order? If restaurants cannot solve these problems, their business will be hurt.
If restaurants can predict how many visitors will be in one day, it&amp;rsquo;s easier for them to make the arrangement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive models on used car evaluation</title>
      <link>https://hyper-potato.github.io/2019-10-06-car-evaluation-using-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hyper-potato.github.io/2019-10-06-car-evaluation-using-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will deploy decision tree, k-NN, logistic regression, NB, SVM to predict the evaluation of the cars based on their characteristics.
More specifically, I will explore how well these techniques perform for several different parameter values.
Present a brief overview of the predictive modeling process, explorations, and discuss my results. Then I will present the final model and discuss its performance in a comprehensive manner (overall accuracy; per-class performance, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>